hey hey what's up my friend so I'm sure
you can agree right that these days you
can learn trading online for free right
you've got things like you know YouTube
chat gbt blog post Tik Tok Instagram and
whatnot but
still most Traders
fail why is that well if you ask me it's
because of this information overload and
when you get information overload you
get conflicting information right this
indicator says bye and then the other
indicator say sells and then the price
action says stay out what do you do and
then you get analysis paralysis should I
buy should I sell maybe I toss a coin
ask my girlfriend ask my wife so if I
were in your shoes right now I
understand how overwhelming this can be
so this is why right if I were to start
trading all over again right here's how
I would approach trading first I would
do
this number one risk management so
here's the thing right there are many
different types of Traders out there who
can profit from the markets you know
you've got options Trader price action
Trader systems Trader swing Trader
crypto
Trader and they can trade the markets in
different manner but there's one thing
that all of them have in common do you
know what's
that that's it risk management yeah
because you can have the best trading
system out there but without proper risk
management you will still lose despite
having the best system out there let let
me prove it to you so here's an example
right so let's say you have a trading
system that has a 50% winning rate and
on average right you achieve a one to
two risk reward reward ratio this means
if you risk a dollar and you are right
you win $2 so two times your initial
risk and let's say you know your next
eight trades right go something along
this lines right where you know L stands
for losing trade lose lose lose loose
lose and then the next four trades are
winner now let me show you the
importance of risk management as you can
tell this over here this so-called
system that I've you know just shared
with you it's a profitable one in the
long run you will make money okay and
let's say there are two Traders John and
Sally okay so let's say John right let's
say John and Sally they both have $1,000
trading account to start with and let's
say John is you know a guy you know
Macho you know let's go home go big or
go home kind of Trader and let's say he
risk $500 on each trade okay so you can
say first trade is a losing trade so-
500 second trade is also a losing trade
minus 500 you can tell that after two
trades John
has he blown up his account on the other
hand let's talk about s is more
conservative right she wants to you know
trade for the long run the next 10 20 30
years instead of risking $500 a trade s
only risk let's say 20 bucks right 2% of
her account so clearly the first four
traits are loser minus 20 - 20 - 20 - 20
and then the next four trades they are
winners winning trades for her and she
didn't get $20 for each trade in fact
she got $40 return for each trade
because it's a one to2 risk reward ratio
her winners are two times the size of a
losses so it's going to be plus 40 + 40
plus 40 and then plus 40 and if you look
at it net right how much did s make so
the total loss is minor $80 total profit
is $160 right so if you look at all her
total profits here it's about $160 her
total loss from here to here it's $8 so
she has a net profit of $80 after these
eight trades and $80 of $1,000 that's
about 8% gain so can you see the
difference two Traders using the same
Trading System One blow up his account
and one made a net profit of 8% so this
is the importance of risk
management and here's the thing right
about risk management is that this is
one of the lowest hanging fruit that you
can tackle it doesn't require you know
rocket science to understand in fact if
you just spend 45 minutes to an hour you
will be able to master risk management
in no time it's just simple math I think
10 or 12 year old kid will be able to do
it and this aspect of risk management
will be relevant to you will be
essential to you the day you start
trading and the day you end your trading
career right maybe you make too much
money and you want to quit trading yeah
risk management will be there with you
every step of the way and you can't say
the same for the strategies the patterns
the stuff that you learn because
sometimes along the way you might change
strategy and stuff like that but risk
management you won't be changing it you
will be you know sticking with it from
the day you start trading and the day
you quit trading so don't neglect this
focus on this at a Get
Go next expose yourself no I don't mean
taking out your T-shirt and you know
showing me showing me your chest right
but expose yourself means you know go
out there and learn as much as possible
as you can about trading because here's
the thing as a new Trader you do not
know what you do not know okay let me
repeat that once again you do not know
what you do not know so go out there
expose yourself and learn as much as you
can about trading you know there are so
many things that you can study you know
things like for example trading
strategies or you can study things like
you know swing trading Trend following
position trading day trading and much
more right so go out there and learn
about all these
different strategies out there there or
if you want to know what type of trading
methods are available you have you know
price action trading options trading
systems trading Etc so you can use
things like you know YouTube Google read
books whatever you know floats your
board and just expose yourself and one
mistake that many Traders make including
myself is that there's no best trading
strategy out there so don't have that
preconceived notion that oh price action
trading you know it's it's it doesn't
rely on lagging indicators this the best
approach right nothing else comes close
no that's not true right every Trading
methodology every trading strategy it
has their pros and cons right after you
know being in this business for more
than 10 of years everything has pros and
cons and the question is are you able to
accept the downside the cons that comes
along with the strategy or method so
this is where you know people say you
know finding a strategy that suits your
personality so the thing is you must
expose yourself out there to see what's
available before you can find something
that suits you be rather than you know
having someone you know sha a method a
strategy down your throat and you and
choke and you know is not meant for you
so no right so once you master risk
management once you have you know
learned the art of not blowing up your
trading account then go out there learn
all the different trading
Styles and approaches out there because
even if you were to hurt yourself maybe
the strategy doesn't work guess what
your risk management will contain the
downside your losses won't be too
Monumental to the point where you blow
up your account so this is why I put
risk management First Once You Nail that
now then we talk about the uh the uh the
methods the strategies that comes along
with it yeah so go out there expose
yourself
and uh these are some keywords and ideas
that you can study further right if you
do not know where to start
yeah number
three focus on a strategy so you would
at this point right expose yourself to
different strategies techniques patterns
and whatnot M might be you know all over
the place so this is where I need you to
focus right Focus so how do you focus
how do you know which strategy to go
with for STS right once you you know
learn quite a bit about trading you
would start to gravitate towards a
certain trading strategy or methodology
it will naturally come right you will
tend to resonate with something
something will make more sense to you
compared to the other stuff so once you
sense that right it's time to focus okay
so how do you focus on a trading
strategy so this is where I need you to
extract the concepts of the strategy
that you want to focus on so let me give
you an example there are many typ of
trading strategies out there Trend
following counter Trend trading mean
reversion trading blah blah blah so
let's say you want to go with a mean
reversion trading strategy all right so
for people who trade a mean reversion
trading strategy for the stock market
right the concepts behind it right is
something like this right just three
Simple Thing number one you're going to
find stocks that are in an uptrend
identify stocks that are in an uptrend
you're going to buy on a pullback and
then you're going to sell the rent that
is the entire concept behind a Min
reversion stock trading strategy so it
actually looks something like this uh
price goes up comes down goes up comes
down pulls back you buy okay and then if
you have a bounce you sell the rally and
you know captur it one small bounce up
higher and if you want to learn more
about mean reversion trading strategy
for the stock market right uh uh this is
a trading system right I actually teach
in my life webinar stock trading secrets
you can see that this system using the
same concept which I've just shared with
you earlier the annual return return is
about 18.46% right and we have tested
said it over the last 20 about 24 years
right and if you want to learn this
system right with the exact trading
rules so what you can do is just go down
to this over here right trading ron.com
ssts right uh stock trading Secrets over
here trading ron.com STS right so this
webinar I know I walk you through the
exact mean reversion trading strategy
when to enter when to sell the rules the
chart examples behind it and all the fun
stuff so if you can make it for this
webinar highly encourage you to join so
we can go into more details yeah but for
now let's move
on okay so also I want to talk about you
know focusing on a strategy right by
focusing on a strategy you also get less
conflict you feel less conflicted why is
that right let me explain why most
conflicts in trading right they they
arise because of different methodologies
right you have heard the same you know
like value investor they look to buy low
and sell high but at the same time you
know momentum Trader Trend follower they
look to buy high and sell higher so now
the question is how do you deal with
with this conflict this guy you know R
tells me to buy low sell high this one
says he can make more money buying High
selling higher who should I follow who
is right who is who is
wrong well the question is
this what are you focusing on are you
focusing on trying to be a value
investor or are you focusing on trying
to be a momentum Trader once you know
what's your focus then you should follow
the approach that's align with your
focus and ignore everything else
everything else is noise make sense so
this is the importance of focusing cuz
once you can focus on a strategy then
all this you realize that all this
conflicting information just kind of
like melt away because you really know
what you're focusing on everything else
outside of it out of outside of it is
Noise Okay and another thing to add
right when we talking about strategy is
this right when you choose a strategy or
a methodology it has to suit your
circumstance let's say you are working
full-time job right one day 8 10 12
hours a day maybe auditor you're doing
14 16 hours a day then it doesn't make
sense to be a day trader where you need
to be glued to the screen you know for
hours each day yeah so you need to find
a strategy that suits your lifestyle
that suits your circumstance as well
okay next we are going to develop the
strategy so once you have understood and
extracted the concepts of a strategy
that you want to focus on we're going to
take that Concepts and turn it into a
trading strategy that we can you know
work on right so how do you take a
Concepts and then Translate into a
strategy I'll show you how so for every
trading strategy or most trading
strategies it needs to answer this four
questions number one what is the market
conditions that you'll be trading number
two what is the entry trigger that gets
you into a trade number three what's the
exit right this could mean your stop
loss and your take profit level and
number four your risk management so let
me use a document over here right and
kind of like you know walk you through
this example right because I think you
guys uh might be a little bit confused
here so the few things that we need
right uh let's call it the Meer okay
market conditions entry trigger exit and
risk management so let's use the mean
reversion Concepts the mean reversion
trading system Concepts that we talked
about earlier so we are looking for
identify stocks in an uptrend Buy on the
pullback sell on the rally okay so you
can see this is the concepts behind the
mean reversion trading system and and
there are few things that we still need
to uh fill in gaps right which you'll
see shortly but first let's talk about
market conditions so you know that for
this particular strategy the of market
conditions that we are trading is stocks
that are in an uptrend so how do we
Define an uptrend a few ways can go
about it for starters I think if this
stock price is above the 200 day moving
average then look for buying
opportunities okay I think that's one
way to go about it another way you can
go is if the stock price forms a series
of higher highs and lows then look for
buying opportunities because that can
also be meaning that the stock is in an
uptrend and if you want to be more
specific right it has to be on the daily
time frame or whatever time frame that
you are trading on okay so this
classifies the market conditions and in
fact I think you're also looking for a
buying on a pullback right so this can
also the pullback part can
be uh let's over here let's say uh entry
right you're looking to buy on a
pullback okay so how do we specify this
criteria you can say that if the stock
price makes a five day low right buy for
example if the stock price makes a new
five day low you can say buy if you want
to be more detailed right you can say if
the stock price you know drops I mean
there another way of writing this drops
10% over the last three days for example
buy so these are all different ways to
to define the pullback and of course if
you really don't to be specific right
you can say things like you know let's
let's let's let's take things a step
further right if the stock price drops
10% over the last 3 days this means that
the pullback has already been formed and
maybe for discretionary Traders you want
to look for confirmation right uh then
wait for a higher close right or a
hammer or whatever all right then buy so
you can see you can specify exactly what
you're looking for before you enter yeah
so this is how you take a a concept and
then translate it into a set of uh rules
to trade it okay so this how is the
entry let's talk about exit right so for
exit uh we are looking to sell on the
rally okay so this means how do we take
profit so for example if the stock price
for example closes higher sell if the
stock price let's say uh reaches
resistance sell right so this are how
you you know can convert that concept
into a set of rules that tells you when
to sell now exit is two parts right your
stop loss and your take profit level so
what about stop loss for this one could
be you know let's say we put it here
stop
loss if the stock price if the stock
price drops 38 from your entry sell
right so this would cover your stop loss
yeah risk management okay so this one
could be as simple as let's say if you
trade stocks uh maybe whole maximum of
five stocks 20% of capital to each stock
that's one way to go going about it or
for those of you who have a predefined
stop loss in place you can say uh 2% Max
stop loss right from entry to SL so
there are different ways to again Define
your risk management but hopefully by
now right you understand how we actually
take
the concepts these Concepts that I
shared with you earlier right and
translate it into a set of rules that
you can then move on to the next
step now the final thing is to test to
test the trading strategy that you've
developed because here's the thing right
you have no idea whether a trading
strategy will work or not right nobody
is going to tell you you have to test it
right either through back testing or
forward testing or maybe working with
others right to help you come up with a
conclusive data to tell you whether
something works or not so there are
generally two ways to test right number
one is what we call back testing this
means that you are testing a trading
strategy across historical data across
the past data and see how it has
performed over time it's kind of like
you know you go on a date meet this girl
for the first time you're not going to
marry her on the first date but you're
digging questions from her right you
know her her past how does she handle
her money how does she handle her
relationship how many EX she has you
know what kind of family background she
has that's kind of like back testing
right your partner right to see whether
she'll be suitable wife material in the
future yeah so for back testing right
for in the context of trading the
advantage is that it's fast you get
feedback a lot faster because you know
if you can you you can let's say do
programming or you can work with someone
right you can you know test trading
systems you know uh many trading systems
right in a short period of time yeah but
the disadvantage of back testing is that
uh usually for those people who are back
testing systematic trading systems right
you require programming knowledge and
it's something that I think not many
Traders would have it right but you can
always hire someone to help you with it
next one is forward testing it's
basically testing a strategy in the live
markets and see how he has you know
performed over time again kind of like
you know meeting the girl for the first
time you do not know her past but you
know guess what let's hang out for the
next three to six months the next one
year and see how she's SL you know let
me travel with her let me see her
sleeping her eating her habits can I you
know deal with it right how does she
squeeze the toothpaste does it you know
annoy me just just does she squeeze it
from the top or the bottom or the middle
yeah that's forward testing
so Advantage is that you know for in a
context of trading it's free for testing
usually you just need some charts
Microsoft Excel will be able to get the
job done disadvantage is that for
testing is slow right you need the the
the trade to happen in real time and it
takes longer compared to someone who
back testing yeah so so from the testing
right you will then know whether a
trading strategy works or not right and
if it works great right you now have a
trading strategy that you can stick with
for a long time and this helps build
your confidence in your strategy in
yourself
and what if the strategy doesn't work
then go back to the drawing board right
going back to refining your strategy
right to see you know how you can
improve on things you know finding out
you know where are the main losses
coming in is it because you know the
losses are too big that's why it's
eating a lot of your profits or maybe
you're trading in a poor Market
condition etc etc so it's only through
the testing can you get feedback and
from that feedback can you then refine
your strategy further to to improve on
it and make it work in the uh in the
long run yeah and of course this process
can be tedious can be difficult so this
is why uh again if you want a kind of
like a shortcut or you want a system a
proven trading system that works you can
join me at this upcoming webinar called
stock trading Secrets right I'll be
happy to with you to share with you this
mean reversion trading system you can
use it as a foundation to build your own
trading strategy so you can you know
save time and avoid going around in
circles right so if that sounds like
something that you'd be interested in
again uh the link is at trading
freer.com STS also put the link
somewhere below this video so you can uh
sign up for it okay and again right uh
this video I've purposely given you a
high level overview of how I would go
about trading the markets if I'm new to
it so we covered many different
components from you know getting exposed
developing a strategy focusing Etc so if
there's anything that You' like me to
cover in more details leave in the
comment section below so I can check it
out and see where or which other areas
you guys need help and I might create a
future video that tackles that question
of yours so with that said I wish you
good luck good trading I will talk to
you soon